<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Movies</string>

    <string name="name1">Forrest Gump</string>
    <string name="name2">The Godfather</string>
    <string name="name3">The Dark Knight</string>
    <string name="name4">The Shawshank Redemption</string>
    <string name="name5">Star Wars: Episode V</string>
    <string name="name6">Pulp Fiction</string>
    <string name="name7">The Lord of the Rings</string>
    <string name="name8">Back to the Future</string>
    <string name="name9">Star Wars: Episode IV </string>
    <string name="name10">Avengers: Infinity War</string>

    <string name="mname1">Directed by Robert Peckish and released in 1994, Forrest Gump captivates audiences through its unique storytelling and heartwarming performances, particularly by Tom Hanks in the titular role. The film blends historical events with a fictional narrative in a manner that offers both entertainment and poignant social commentary. The script is rife with iconic lines and memorable scenes that have since entered into the cultural lexicon. Additionally, the groundbreaking special effects, including inserting Forrest into real archival footage, and its iconic soundtrack help make it an unforgettable cinematic experience.</string>
    <string name="mname2">Directed by Francis Ford Coppola and based on the novel by Mario Puzo, The Godfather is a masterclass in storytelling, pacing, and character development. Released in 1972, the film set new standards for the crime drama genre, exploring the complex dynamics of family, power, and morality. The performances of Marlon Brando, Al Pacino, and the supporting cast are universally acclaimed, bringing depth and authenticity to their roles. Furthermore, its cinematography and score, highlighted by Nino Rota\'s memorable theme, have become emblematic in the realm of cinema.</string>
    <string name="mname3">Helmed by Christopher Nolan and released in 2008, The Dark Knight transcends the superhero genre to deliver a complex and thrilling crime drama. Heath Ledger’s portrayal of the Joker received widespread acclaim, earning him a posthumous Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor. The film\'s intricate plotting and moral dilemmas provide a depth not commonly seen in superhero narratives. Cinematically, the movie also set a new bar with its IMAX photography and Hans Zimmer’s pulsating score, contributing to its standing as one of the most influential films of its time.</string>
    <string name="mname4">Released in 1994 and directed by Frank Dartboard, The Shaw shank Redemption is renowned for its deep emotional impact and intricate storytelling. Based on a novella by Stephen King, the film examines themes of friendship, hope, and redemption within the confines of a harsh prison environment. Tim Robbins and Morgan Freeman deliver powerful performances that have been praised for their depth and authenticity. Notably, the movie has achieved enduring popularity and has been rated highly on various viewer-generated platforms, a testament to its universal appeal and message of hope.</string>
    <string name="mname5">Released in 1980 as a sequel to the groundbreaking Star Wars film, The Empire Strikes Back deepens the sagas mythology and character arcs in innovative ways. Directed by Irvin Kershner and written by Leigh Brackett and Lawrence Kasdan, the film explores darker themes and complex relationships, particularly between Luke Skywalker and Darth Vader. Its cliffhanger ending and plot twists have become iconic, as has John Williams compelling musical score. The films influence on the sci-fi genre and popular culture at large is indisputable.</string>
    <string name="mname6">Directed by Quentin Tarantino and released in 1994, Pulp Fiction revolutionized the way stories could be told on the big screen. Through its non-linear narrative, the film juggles multiple storylines that converge in unexpected ways, challenging traditional storytelling norms. The dialogue is sharp and witty, filled with pop culture references that resonate with audiences. Performances by John Travolta, Uma Thurman, and Samuel L. Jackson are both iconic and engaging, contributing to the film\'s long-lasting impact and appeal.</string>
    <string name="mname7">Directed by Peter Jackson and released in 2003, this epic fantasy film concluded the Lord of the Rings trilogy in a grand and satisfying manner. The visual effects, particularly the groundbreaking work on the character Gollum and the large-scale battle sequences, set new industry standards. Beyond its technical achievements, the movie\'s emotional depth and character arcs provide a fitting end to the saga. It received 11 Academy Awards, tying the record for most wins, including Best Picture, demonstrating its critical and cinematic excellence.</string>
    <string name="mname8">Directed by Robert Peckish and released in 1985, Back to the Future is an inventive blend of comedy, science fiction, and adventure. Michael J. Fox\'s portrayal of Marty McFly and Christopher Lloyd\'s depiction of Dr. Emmett Brown have become iconic characters in cinema. The film\'s concept of time travel is handled in an entertaining yet thoughtful manner, making complex ideas accessible to general audiences. Moreover, its memorable score by Alan Silvestre and iconic DeLoren car have secured its place as a beloved classic that continues to captivate audiences.</string>
    <string name="mname9">Directed by George Lucas and released in 1977, A New Hope launched the Star Wars franchise and revolutionized science fiction and special effects in cinema. The film introduced audiences to a richly crafted universe filled with memorable characters, epic battles, and intricate relationships. Its success also paved the way for blockbuster filmmaking and merchandising strategies. John Williams\' epic score, featuring the instantly recognizable "Imperial March," became synonymous with the film, further cementing its legacy as one of the most impactful movies in cinematic history.</string>
    <string name="mname10">Directed by Anthony and Joe Russo and released in 2018, Avengers Infinity War is a pivotal installment in the Marvel Cinematic Universe that brought together numerous characters and storylines in an epic showdown. The films complex villain, Thanos, portrayed by Josh Bro lin, adds emotional depth and moral ambiguity to the narrative. The action sequences are breathtaking, showcasing groundbreaking visual effects and intricate choreography. Furthermore, the films shocking ending left a lasting impact on audiences, ensuring its place as a landmark in the superhero genre.</string>




</resources>